Akshay Patil

Frontend Web Developer

Address Vettersstraße 70 Chemnitz, Saxony, 09126 Germany

Phone 491-768-7002864

E-mail 04akshayp@gmail.com



Solution-driven Front end Developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS,JavaScript, BOOTSTRAP,REACT and ANGULAR. Built products for desktop andmobile app users over 3+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

Work History

2020-12 - 2022-03 Front End Web Developer Intern

Spontom Ventures Private Limited, VISAKHAPATNAM, India

- Developed user interfaces with React JS, Angular TS, JavaScript, HTML5 , CSS3 and BOOTSTRAP.
- Troubleshot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.
- Designed and implemented web components across new and existing designs.
- Studied basic project requirements with assigned technical lead and planned development strategies.
- Analyzed, prioritized and problem-solved several tasks concurrently with minimum supervision.

2019-09 - 2020-02 Web Developer Intern

MACH 15 EDGE SOLUTIONS, Ghaziabad, India

- Developed user interfaces with React js, Angular Typescript , HTML5,BOOTSTRAP and CSS3.
- Designed and implemented web components across new and existing designs.
- Handled and supervised team of 4 web developer interns.
- Participated in project development through entire Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC).
- Attended corporate learning and development programs to gain competencies and professional skills.

Education

2021-10 - Current	Master of Science: Web Engineering
-------------------	------------------------------------

Technische Universität Chemnitz - Germany

2016-01 - 2020-01 Bachelor of Engineering (B.E): Computer Science

Walchand Institute of Technology - India

GPA: 8.16/10

Skills

HTML	
CSS	
React	
JavaScript	
Angular	
Bootstrap	

Languages

English	Excellent
German	Basic

Certifications

2020-06	Advanced Styling with Responsive Design by University of Michigan
2019-09	Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4 by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2019-09	Front-End Web Development with React by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2019-09	Server-side Development with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2019-09	Multiplatform Mobile App Development with React Native by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
2019-01	Single page Web development with Angular typescript by Internshala Trainings

Work Samples

Github https://github.com/AkshayPatil4

Blogento https://blogento-32d54.firebaseapp.com/home